Inventory of the Thomas Byrne Edsall papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Announcement of a lecture by Thomas and Mary Edsall (authors of Chain Reaction: The Impact of Race, Rights and Taxes on American Politics), The Michigan Journalism fellows, Rackham School of Graduate Studies, University of Michigan, 1992 November 10 (Box-folder 89: 12)
  Includes a letter from Charles R. Eisendrath commending them on their presentation
- Fan mail, 1985-1996 (Box-folder 89: 13)
- A memorandum from Lynn Chu, 1994, and a note from Raye? (Box-folder 89: 14)
- Chester W. Hartman, 1992 (Box-folder 89: 15)
- Doug Hibbs, 1993 (Box-folder 89: 16)
- David C. Hsia, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 89: 17)
  Printed copies of articles
- Japan, 1994 (Box-folder 89: 18)
  Correspondence with Shigeo Tobita regarding the translation of Chain Reaction into Japanese
- Jim Jaffe, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 89: 19)
  Writings and notes
- Robbie Kahn, 1996 (Box-folder 89: 20)
- Miscellany, 1988-1997 (Box-folder 89: 21)
- 2 3.5-inch computer disks labeled "back up,", undated (Box 89)
- Billy Schmilk, 1981 (Box-folder 90: 1)
- Organization, 1976 (Box-folder 90: 2)
  Articles by Thomas Edsall
- Organization--Baltimore, 1976 (Box-folder 90: 3)
- Tony Waters, 1977 (Box-folder 90: 4)
  Typescript paper
- Nursery school-—Class list, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 90: 5)
- House, 15 Walker Street, 1958-1980 (Box-folder 90: 6)
  Includes 2 photographic prints depicting the house
- 27 3.5-inch computer disks labeled "back up" (Box 90)
- Miscellany, 1990-1991 (Box 90)
  Cancelled checks, credit union check registers, memoranda from Phi Beta Kappa regarding an order, and pay stubs from the Washington Post
- Miscellany, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 91: 1)
  Clippings, letter from Maryland Automobile Insurance Fund, notebook, and a report from the state treasurer of Maryland
- Ideas-—Article, copy of printed articles, and letters to J. Joseph Curran and Bruce T. Adams regarding the activities of certain legislative agents, 1973 (Box-folder 91: 2)
- Book ideas and notes on Marvin Mandel, undated, and text of his state-of-the state speech, 1973 (Box-folder 91: 3)
- Lobbying, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 91: 4)
  Letters, printed matter, and statement of financial interests
- Last will and testament of Louisa Kamin, 1970 (Box-folder 91: 5)
- Albert Knight and Anthony, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 91: 6)
  Correspondence of Thomas and Mary and Mr. and Mrs. Albert Knight, Sr., with Park School, letters from Mary Edsall to Louis A. Herstein, Jr., notes, clipping, and general information
- Personal correspondence, 1967 – 1970 July (Box-folder 91: 7-8)
- Calendar and sketches, undated (Box 91)
- J. Glen Beall, Jr., undated (Box-folder 92: 1)
  Clippings, fragment of a typescript article about Beall, and miscellany, 1970
- Thomas Edsall's clips, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 92: 2-3)
- Duncan Kennedy-—Contract, 1976 (Box-folder 92: 4)
- "Money and Politics in Maryland"-—Manuscript, 1973 (Box-folder 92: 5)
- Thomas Edsall's notes, 1974 (Box-folder 92: 6-7)
- Various versions of "Money and Politics in Maryland,", 1973-1974 (Box-folder 92: 8)
- Agreement between Irvin Kovens, Irving T. Schwartz, Robert Stofberg, and Robert and Barbara Crancer and Shenandoah Corporation, 1971 (Box-folder 92: 9)
- Information about Marvin Mandel-—Racetrack, etc., 1969-1975 (Box-folder 92: 10-11)
- "Money and Politics in Maryland"--First drafts, undated (Box-folder 93: 1)
- Information regarding Marvin Mandel's divorce, 1973 (Box-folder 93: 2)
- I. K. and W. L. A.?, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 93: 3)
- Common Cause—-Contributors, 1972 (Box-folder 93: 4)
- The Blacks, undated (Box-folder 93: 5)
- Election-—Baltimore, Maryland.
  - Mayoral election, undated (Box-folder 93: 6)
  - Mayoral primary, 1971 September (Box-folder 93: 7)
- Albert Knight, 1971 (Box-folder 93: 8)
  Bulletin, letters, receipt, and information about financial program
- Alexandra-—Park School, 1971
  Includes brochure, letters, and related materials
- Acknowledgement of Thomas Edsall's admission to the Graduate school, Boston University, 1967
- Harvard University-—Student information, 1971
- "What I Did on My Holidays," Tony Waters (age 8) for his mother, Mary Deutsch Edsall, 1982 (Box-folder 93: 9)
- Tony Water-—3rd party beneficiary, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 93: 10)
  Case law, controversy, and chaos
- "The Corbin Connection,", 1982 (Box-folder 93: 11)
- Tony-—Stock exchange cases, undated (Box-folder 93: 12)
- "The Great Case: Of Lawrence versus Fox," Anthony J. Waters, 1980 (Box-folder 93: 13)
- Fan mail, 1978-1985 (Box-folder 94: 1)
- Personal correspondence, 1981 (Box-folder 94: 2)
- Jobs, freelance articles, and Nieman Foundation tries, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 94: 3)
- Correspondence with Morning Sun and Sun information, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 94: 4)
- Michael C. D. Macdonald, 1974 (Box-folder 94: 5)
- Random campaign literature, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 94: 6)
- Photographic negatives, undated (Box-folder 94: 7)
- Legislature story, 1971 April (Box-folder 94: 8)
- Letter and reply about first Washington Monthly piece, 1972 (Box-folder 94: 9)
- Fan mail--"Money" piece, 1972 (Box-folder 94: 10)
- Handouts on the press-— Oregon Ridge Sun papers? Symposium, 1974 April 30 (Box-folder 94: 11)
- Thomas Edsall—"Money" piece, undated (Box-folder 94: 12)
- Registration application for an AKC dog named after Idi Amin, 1979 (Box-folder 94: 13)
- Joe Foote, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 94: 14)
  Harvard Law School report, class of 1960, and clippings
- "Speak the Truth and the Words Will Come," poem, undated (Box-folder 94: 15)
- Correspondence-—Parents, 1974 (Box-folder 94: 16)
- Mary Edsall-—Summary of an article? from the School of Law, University of Maryland, 1982 (Box-folder 94: 17)
- Robert C. Carroll-—Paper, 1976 (Box-folder 94: 18)
- Children's books-—Sketches, undated (Box-folder 94: 19)
- House ideas, 1976 (Box-folder 94: 20)
- Covington & Burling, 1975 (Box-folder 94: 21)
  Letter and invoice for legal service
- Kevin Brown-—Angola, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 94: 22)
- Tupper, Adams & Company, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 94: 23)
  Financial records
- Fred Hill-—Article, 1976? (Box-folder 94: 24)
- Christmas poems, 1977 (Box-folder 94: 25)
- C. G. Sloan-—Appraisal certificate, 1978 (Box-folder 94: 26)
- Mandel reinstated, Cramer, undated (Box-folder 94: 27)
- Interviews.
  - John T. Edsall and others, Harvard Today, undated (Box-folder 94: 28)
  - Glenn Gould, Rolling Stone, by Jonathan Cott, 1974 (Box 94)
- "Money and Politics in Maryland,", undated (Box-folder 95: 1)
- The Sun Papers, undated (Box-folder 95: 2)
  Organizational chart, clippings, and note
- Albert Knight-—College admission papers, and autobiographical statement, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 95: 3)
- Thomas Edsall's funny papers, 1976-1986 (Box-folder 95: 4-5)
- Letters from Maryland Center for Public Broadcasting regarding Thomas Edsall's services, 1970, and a letter of appreciation (Box-folder 95: 6)
- Thomas Edsall's memorabilia, 1973-1987 (Box-folder 95: 7-8)
  Includes his press cards; announcement of his winning the first prize, Guild Front Page Awards; 1 photographic print depicting Thomas Edsall with an unidentified individual, undated; and 1 photographic print depicting Thomas Edsall playing Carl Levin, senator from Michigan, Capital Hill Squash Club, 1983
- Gordon Chaplin, 1974 (Box-folder 95: 9)
- House, travel, and recipes, 1971-1976 (Box-folder 96: 1)
- George R. Sands & Sons-—Drawing of the memorial and a letter, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 96: 2)
- 35 photographic prints depicting the Edsall family; his parents' marriage certificate, 1933; and Thomas Edsall's birth certificate, 1941 (Box-folder 96: 3)
  Includes 1 contact sheet
- Katherine Edsall, 1978 (Box-folder 96: 4)
  Burial, memorial service program, and obituary. Includes a photograph of her memorial marker
- Thomas Edsall's college data, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 96: 5)
- Dr. Neel Simon, 1970 (Box-folder 96: 6)
- Tarock, undated (Box-folder 96: 7)
  Typescript information
- Margaret Deutsch Carroll. Clipping for wedding announcement, 1970, and resume, undated (Box-folder 96: 8)
- Personal correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 96: 9)
- George Washington University. (Box-folder 96: 10)
  Letter, 1974, and information regarding tailor, doctor, and ear doctor
- Campaign, 1976 (Box-folder 96: 11)
  Gerald Ford's Wisconsin trip memorabilia
- Providence Journal clips, 1965 (Box-folder 96: 12)
- Blue Cross-—Vista Volunteer Program, undated, and selective service system classification card, 1967 (Box-folder 96: 13)
- Job applications, 1970 (Box-folder 96: 14)
- Chicory, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 96: 15)
  Includes 1 photographic print depicting a lady with George Harvey Gilliam, who died in Vietnam, 1968 April
- W. W. Norton & Company. (Box-folder 96: 16)
  Includes correspondence, 1983, questionnaires, undated, and a Guide to Word Processing Conversion (WPC) for automated typesetting, undated
- Articles about Irvin Kovens by Jerome Kelly and about Marvin Mandel by Jerry Oppenheimer, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 97: 1)
- House, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 97: 2)
- Light verses by others, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 97: 3)
- Washington Post/Potomac, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 97: 4)
- Writing by Thomas Edsall, letter from Michael C. Janeway, and notebooks, 1968 (Box-folder 97: 5)
- Christmas cards, 1976 (Box-folder 97: 6)
- Political and movement-—memorabilia, 1972 (Box-folder 97: 7)
  Includes 4 photographic prints depicting Governor Marvin Mandel with his signature on the print
- Mary Edsall—Rejections of poems, financial records, and letters (Box 98)
  (photocopies)
  - 1969-1975 (Box-folder 98: 1)
  - 1973-1974 (Box-folder 98: 2)
  - 1974 (Box-folder 98: 3)
  - 1975-1976 (Box-folder 98: 4)
- Personal mail, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 98: 5)
- Thomas and Mary Edsall-—School publications, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 98: 6)
- Thomas Edsall-—Shady Hill report cards, 1946-1956 (Box-folder 99: 1)
- Legislative reform speech, 1973 November (Box-folder 99: 2)
- Clippings, reproductions of Thomas Edsall's photographs, 1967-1981 (Box-folder 99: 3)
  Includes 2 photographic prints, undated and 1950, depicting unidentified individuals
- Friends, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 99: 4)
  Clippings, letters, notes, postcards, and receipts. Includes 1 photographic print depicting an unidentified lady, undated
- Anthony Knight, letter from school to Mr. and Mrs. Albert Knight, list of colleges, and note about Anthony, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 99: 5)
- Journalism contests, 1972 (Box-folder 99: 6)
- Christmas cards, 1974 (Box-folder 99: 7)
- Marvin Mandel, 1973 (Box-folder 99: 8)
- Writings by Margaret S. Beadle, 1987 (Box-folder 99: 9)
  Includes undated articles
- Memorandum-— New York Times, 1972 (Box-folder 99: 10)
  Neighborhood organizations, Baltimore, Maryland
- Chicory, 1967 (Box-folder 99: 11)
- Painting-—Information, 1966 (Box-folder 99: 12)
- People to write, condolences, etc., 1976-1977 (Box-folder 99: 13)
- 14 photographic prints including 12 depicting Thomas Edsall, and 2 depicting other unidentified individuals, undated (Box 99)
- Personal correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 100: 1)
- Job tries, 1971, 1980 (Box-folder 100: 2-3)
- Thomas and Mary Edsall-—Last will and testament, undated (Box-folder 100: 4)
- Resume, 1981 (Box-folder 100: 5)
- Edsall genealogy, undated (Box-folder 100: 6)
- Leaving Evening Sun party, 1974 (Box-folder 100: 7)
  Citation of contempt, memorandum, and proclamation
- Freelance tries, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 100: 8)
- 901 Tyson Street. Car insurance, homeowner's policy, and other documents relating to the property (Box-folder 100: 9)
- Ropes & Gray, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 101: 1)
  Correspondence with the Edsalls and other documents relating to Katherine Edsall's estate
- Thomas Edsall-—Memorabilia, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 101: 2)
- Letters regarding publication of "Money and Politics in Maryland,", 1973-1974 (Box-folder 101: 3)
- Transaction IV, article, 1974 (Box-folder 101: 4)
- Hal?, 1981 (Box-folder 101: 5)
- Karl W. and Ruth Deutsch, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 101: 6)
  Letters, clippings, and postcards
- Hal and Margaret Carroll, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 101: 7)
  Letters and clippings
- Albert Knight, 1979 (Box-folder 101: 8)
  Letter and postcard
- Gutten Stein, 1979 (Box-folder 101: 9)
  Letters to Mary Edsall
- Personal correspondence, 1969 (Box-folder 101: 10)
- Clippings, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 101: 11)
- Race tracks, 1935, 1975 (Box-folder 101: 12)
  Notes, printed matter, and agreement to pay loan
- "Organization"--Final corrected version, 1977 January 9 (Box-folder 101: 13)
- Article (with Sarbanes?), 1976 (Box-folder 101: 14)
- Notes of condolence-—Death of Thomas Edsall's mother, 1978 (Box-folder 101: 15)
- Katherine Edsall-—Death certificate, 1978 (Box-folder 101: 16)
- Karl and Ruth Deutsch-—Memorabilia, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 101: 17)
- Miscellany, 1981-1982 (Box 101)
  Letters, postcard, and telegram
- Clippings, 1981, flight certificate, poem written on the occasion of Thomas Edsall's 40th birthday, undated (Box 102)
- Democratic conflicts, 1985-1995 (Box-folder 103: 1-3)
  Brochures, clippings, printed matter, newsletters, and polling data
- Democratic polls, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 103: 4)
  Clippings, printed matter, articles, and abstract of a paper
- Clippings, printed matter, and data regarding senate races, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 103: 5-7)
- Right wing, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 103: 8)
  Form letter, list of groups declaring their opposition to George McGovern, and printed matter
- GOP, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 103: 9)
  Clippings and remarks by Frank J. Fahrenkopf Jr.
- Douglas Edsall-—Resume, undated (Box-folder 104: 1)
- Bob Putnam, article, 1995 (Box-folder 104: 2)
- Gerald Holton, article, 1992 (Box-folder 104: 3)
- William Drayton, articles, 1997 (Box-folder 104: 4)
- Shirley Hoffenberg, undated (Box-folder 104: 5)
  Note
- Thomas and Mary Edsall-—Day lists, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 104: 6)
- Betty Friedman, 1996 (Box-folder 104: 7)
  Article. Typescript
- Democratic inversion, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 104: 8)
  Conference papers and survey. Includes an empty folder with a note on the cover from Jennifer L. Hochschild to Thomas Edsall
- Democratic Leadership Council (DLC), 1985-1990 (Box-folder 104: 9)
  Clippings, newsletters, reports, and remarks by Charles S. Robb
- GOP and blacks, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 104: 10-11)
  Clippings, printed matter, and report
- GOP cadre, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 104: 12)
- Democrats, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 104: 13)
  Clippings, printed matter, lists of National Committee members and remarks, delegate selection rules, and national platform
- Renaissance Weekend, South Carolina, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 105: 1-2)
- Susan J. Tolchin, 1997 (Box-folder 105: 3)
  Letter of recommendation from Thomas Edsall and a project proposal by Tolchin
- John Coale, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 105: 4)
- Alice Rossi, 1964 (Box-folder 105: 5)
  Article. Photocopy
- GOP accommodation, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 105: 6)
  Articles, clippings, and printed matter
- National Center for Education Statistics, 1996 (Box-folder 106: 1)
  Digest
- Sexual revolution by John Heidenry, 1997 (Box-folder 106: 2)
- Paternalism, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 106: 3)
- Writings by Thomas Edsall and others for the New York Review of Books, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 106: 4-5)
- Union membership, undated (Box-folder 106: 6)
- U.S. News story ideas, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 106: 7-8)
- Beef-—Profits of meatpacking, 1996 (Box-folder 106: 9)
- Biotech, 1997 (Box-folder 106: 10)
- Walter Kirn, 1997 (Box-folder 106: 11)
- Chip Turner, undated (Box-folder 106: 12)
  Resume
- Matt Lait, 1997 (Box-folder 106: 13)
- Difference-—Male/female, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 106: 14)
- Alan Patricof, 1997 (Box-folder 106: 15)
  Biographical information
- Thomas Edsall-—Information about his upcoming book, 1997 (Box-folder 106: 16)
  Includes announcement of a discussion by Thomas Edsall and 1 photographic print depicting him, undated
- William H. Frey, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 106: 17)
  Article and research reports
- Miscellany, 1986-1996
  Letters to Thomas and Mary Edsall, Michael Flanagan's letter to the Washington Post, clippings, Mary's day lists, and an article by Thomas Edsall
- Clippings and printed matter, 1983 (Box-folder 107: 1)
- "Money and Politics in Maryland,", undated (Box 107)
- The Four Star Salute Committee, campaign fund report, 1973 (Box 107)
  List of contributions and receipts, disbursements, and schedule of cash balance, and outstanding debt
- Composition book, undated (Box 107)
- "Attitudes of Negroes in Various Cities," report, undated (Box 107)
- Black business directory, 1973-1974 (Box 107)
- Trenton Democratic Club 45th annual ball, 1973 (Box 107)
- Baltimore Municipal Handbook, 1969 (Box 107)
- Notebooks, undated
- Miscellany, 1970-1975 (Box 107)
  Fragment of an article by Thomas Edsall, clippings, printed matter, letters, various lists, and maps
- Unprinted Alabama legislature story by Thomas Edsall, undated (Box-folder 108: 1)
- Random Sun papers introduction, 1971 (Box-folder 108: 2)
- Joseph G. Cannon, 1971 (Box-folder 108: 3)
  Articles, clippings, and related materials
- Katy Deutsch--Yale University notebook for English, undated (Box 108)
- Articles by Thomas Edsall and others, 1971-1972 (Box 108)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1970-1974 (Box 108)
- Report to the Governor of Maryland from the Department of Licensing and Regulation, 1971 (Box 108)
- Kodak photographic paper, negatives, 2 35mm slides, 50 mm Omegar lens (Box 108)
- Miscellany, 1970-1971 (Box 108)
  Various data, invitations, lists, and a button labeled "come home, Sarge!"
- Photographs--79 loose color and 80 color 35mm slides in boxes, negatives, and Kodak guide book for black-and-white photography, undated (Box-folder 109: 1-3)
- Photographs-8 35mm slides and negatives, undated (Box-folder 110: 1-2)
- Writings of Thomas Edsall and related materials, 1972 (Box-folder 110: 3-4)
  Typescript and clippings
- Jamestown Youth Corps, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 110: 5-6)
  Budget outline, clippings, printed matter, memoranda, notes, press release, and project proposal
- Thomas Edsall file, 1974 (Box-folder 110: 7)
  Clippings, letters, list of attorneys, notes, press release, request for inspection of reports and statements, and weekly report
- Clippings, 1971-1972 (Box 110)
- Friends of Beall (J. Glenn Beall)--Schedule of receipts and disbursements, undated (Box 110)
- Survey of political attitudes, Maryland, 1973 (Box 110)
- Miscellany, 1973 (Box 110)
- Sun clips for Post application, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 111: 1)
- Thomas Edsall's best clips, 1972-1984 (Box-folder 111: 2-7)
- Day Lists (Box 112)
  - 1985-1993 (Box-folder 112: 1)
  - 1986 (Box-folder 112: 2)
  - 1986-1987 (Box-folder 112: 3)
  - 1987-1988 (Box-folder 112: 4)
  - 1988-1990 (Box-folder 112: 5)
- The Atlantic, 1991 May (Box 112)
- Notebook-—Campaign fund, undated (Box 112)
- Brochure-—The Merchants Club of Baltimore City, 1968 (Box 112)
- Conference papers and writings by others, 1991 (Box 113)
- Thomas Edsall's writings, interviews, and related materials, 1984-1992 (Box 113)
- Leadership Conference Education Fund, 1990 (Box 113)
  Annual report, articles, newsletter, and schedule
- Clippings and printed matter, 1990-1992 (Box 113)
- Democratic Party-—Information relating to the organization, platform, and strategy, 1991-1992 (Box 113)
- The Atlantic, 1991 May (Box 113)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1989-1990 (Box 114)
- Writings by others, 1988-1991 (Box 114)
- Thomas Edsall's writings, 1990 (Box 114)
  Articles, typescript chapters, and fragments
- Transcripts of Jesse Helms' TV-ad Iraq/Gantt defense spending cuts, 1990 (Box 114)
- Democratic Party related materials, 1988-1992 (Box 114)
- Thomas Edsall's clippings about Marvin Mandel, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 115: 1)
- Clippings, 1992 (Box-folder 115: 2)
- Logs-—daily diaries.
  Includes notes for books
  - Undated (Box-folder 115: 3)
  - 1985-1986 (Box-folder 115: 4-5)
  - 1987-1989 (Box-folder 115: 6)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1990-1994 (Box 115)
- Miscellany-—Notes, undated (Box 115)
- Beverly LaHaye, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 116: 1)
  Brochures, itinerary, program schedule, and information regarding Concerned Women for America (CWA) convention, clippings, and printed matter
- Moral Majority, 1985 May 23 (Box-folder 116: 2)
  Interview of Robert Godwin and others by Thomas Edsall. Typescript
- Sun Myung Moon, 1985 July 15 (Box-folder 116: 3)
- "Christian Voice," article by Thomas Edsall, 1985 November 24 (Box-folder 116: 4)
- Book flap: key points of book on race, 1990 April 29 (Box-folder 116: 5)
- "Christmas—South," article by Thomas Edsall, 1986 May 11 (Box-folder 116: 6)
- Christians, 1986 (Box-folder 116: 7)
- Articles by Thomas Edsall, 1983-1991 (Box 116)
- Printed matter, 1948-1989 (Box 116)
- Charts, exit polls, interviews of focus groups, lists of Political Action Committee (PAC) receipts, and statistical data relating to the upcoming election, 1988 (Box 116)
- Brochures, reports, schedule of the annual meeting of the American Political Science Association, and resource guide to the 1990 elections, 1982-1990 (Box 116)
- Earl Black, 1988 (Box 116)
- Interviews on quotas by Thomas Edsall, 1990 (Box-folder 117: 1)
- Articles by Thomas Edsall, 1980-1991 (Box 117)
- Polling report, press release for Richard Thornburgh senate campaign, clippings, printed matter, various reports, and issues of The Washington Monthly and Dissent, 1972-1991 (Box 117)
- Clippings and printed matter, including from the Sun, 1976-1987 (Box-folder 118: 1)
- Clipping-— Washington Post, 1987 (Box 118)
- Issues of Dissent, 1979-1987 (Box 118)
- Thomas Edsall-—Clippings from the Baltimore Evening Sun, 1969 April (Box 118)
  (bound scrapbook)
- Various journals, 1974-1987 (Box 118)
  Some include Thomas Edsall's articles. Printed copy
- Clippings--Thomas Edsall. (Box 119)
  Bound scrapbooks
  - 1968 April – 1969 March
  - 1969 March – 1976 February
    Includes 3 photographic prints, 1 depicting unidentified woman; 1 depicting Joseph H. Rash, Irving Kovens, and Mervin Shpritz; and 1 depicting Marvin Mandel with his signature on it
  - 1969 April – 1977 December 4
- Clippings, 1987 (Box 119)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1984-1990 (Box-folder 120: 1)
- Article on black split by Thomas Edsall for the New Republic, 1989 June (Box-folder 120: 2)
- Various journals, 1985-1990 (Box 120)
- Clippings of Thomas Edsall, Baltimore Evening Sun, 1967 January - 1970 February (Box 120)
- 1 photographic print depicting Thomas Edsall with Edmund S. Muskie?, undated (Box 120)
- Miscellany--Note, undated, and an invitation to celebrate the publication of The New Politics of Inequality, 1984 June 15 (Box 120)
- Master list of stories, 1987 August 1 (Box-folder 121: 1)
- "Power and Money," clippings
  - Corrected printout and introduction, 1987 July (Box-folder 121: 2)
  - Introduction and final versions, 1987 August (Box-folder 121: 3)
- "Mid-life Crisis Feared: Edsall Arrested," the Washington Post, 1981 August 22 (Box-folder 121: 4-7)
- Writings of Thomas Edsall. Typescript fragments of chapters from "Power and Money" and "Legacy,", 1987 (Box 121)
- Dissent, 1987 (Box 121)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1981-1987 (Box 121)
- Miscellany--Notes, undated (Box 121)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1971 March 11 - 1987 July 16 (Box-folder 122: 1-3)
- Frame shop--Laminate. 3 photographic prints depicting unidentified individuals and 1 photographic print depicting Thomas Edsall, Tip O'Neil, Kirk O'Donnell, John Petrocik, and Warren Miller, undated (Box-folder 122: 4)
  Includes New York Review of Books, 1989 April 13
- Scrapbook, 1988 (Box-folder 122: 5)
- Xerox copies of articles, 1988 June 6 - 1989 February (Box-folder 122: 6)
- Scrapbook, 1985 November 3 – 1987 August (Box-folder 122: 7)
  Includes duplicate resumes
- Dissent, 1986 Fall (Box 122)
- Clippings, 1982 August 28 (Box-folder 123: 1)
- Norton clips book, 1987 July 23 - August 30 (Box-folder 123: 2)
  Includes written chapters, contract, notes, and printed matter